In this video, I will show you how to create a design for Marvelous Designer.
Welcome to the summer atmosphere series tutorial.
This series of tutorials is intended to help beginners understand the basic operations of Marvelous Designer.
Before we start, we need to go to the drawing window, double click on the Avatar folder and open it.
Then select the Stylize folder and double click on Hana.
Open the Motion folder and type in the Neutral Idle action file.
Please confirm that you have selected the position where the costume and virtual model move to the start of the action, and the first position to be converted to the action at the bottom.
Click on the triangle at the bottom of the software and open the animation editor.
Change the type of play to real-time.
Click on the Play button to preview the character animation.
After checking, reset the current frame to the start position.
Open the costume and virtual model folder at the top of the drawing window again.
Choose to load the blue dresser.
Delete all versions.
Select all versions and reduce their particle diameter to 12.
This will reduce the details of the costume, but will speed up the overall simulation speed, which is faster than the previous one.
Delete the excess collar and sleeve versions.
Adjust the waistline.
Adjust the waistline to make them shorter in the horizontal and vertical directions.
Adjust the waistline to make the costume longer.
Use the whatever tool to select all the bottom points of the dresser, and drag them down to add an extended dresser.
Open thecivilize.
Then move the back of the top coat to the front and adjust the belt position
Select the top coat bottom and move them up to shorten the length of the top coat
If the top coat is too short, you can move the bottom down a little bit to simulate it
Adjust the belt position to make it narrower and more intimate
Press Shift Z to show the length of the top coat
This will help you match the seam line more quickly
The mouse is on the tool
Click on the small scissors icon to make a pull-down menu
Select the seam line tool and select the seam line between the belt and the top coat
You will see that the gap between the seam lines is red, which means the gap is larger
Use the seam line tool to move the bottom point of the top coat inside
Until it is close to the belt line
Use the same operation for the back coat
You can adjust the size of the front coat or press Alt plus W to move the front coat to the full screen
Click the small scissors to separate the shape tool.
Use the edit shape tool to adjust the panel like in the video.
Adjusting the panel in the 3D window is very intuitive and can quickly adjust to the ideal effect.
These changes will also work on the 2D panel at the same time.
Click the button at the bottom right of the software to adjust the window layout.
Adjust the chest side of the throat to make clothes more suitable for human body shapes.
The chest side of the chest is also adjusted to the 2D panel.
Slip the point of the throat, widen the throat, and cover the fold position.
After opening the model, you can continue to adjust the point of the throat if you do not have a flat dress.
Activate the model, drag the lower body of the dress to help the dress be more flat.
Open the Substance folder at the top of the window.
These Adobe Substance materials are highly editable, just like in Substance Painter.
Select the Flect Tartan material and drag it onto the skirt fabric.
Next, go to the Hardware and Trims folder, select the Ribbon folder and drag it to the 3D window.
Click to confirm the download, and move it to the right position, like in the video.
Click on the small watermark on the upper right of the positioning ball, and then move the mouse to the right position.
Click to stick the butterfly knot on it.
After opening the simulation, pause the simulation, adjust the position of the butterfly knot, and simulate again.
You may need multiple tests to get the best results.
Click on the name of the 2D version window, and switch to the UV Editor window in the drop-down menu.
In the Background tab on the right, select to place all UVs at 0.1, and then adjust the UV image.
In the Background tab on the left, select to place allows UV image.
Click on the name of the 2D version window, and switch to the UV editor window.
Click on the name of the 2D version window, and switch to the UV image button to open the Disneyland.
The 2D version window is now installed.
Next, выблуш
And chain these and move to the bottom right corner of the simulation.
Adjust the properties in the shape editor.
You can adjust the color of the fabric according to your needs.
After the recording is complete, you can export the Alembic file. Here we select default settings.
After that, you can continue to render costumes and mission models in the 3D software you often use.
Welcome to the tutorial of other summer atmosphere series, to learn how to make other content in this scene.